Preliminary Guide to the Junaluska School of Religion Records, 1928 - 1941
Duke University. University Archives
Junaluska School of Religion records 1928 - 1941
Duke School of Religion
3 linear feet Extent: 3000 Items
Duke University. University Archives
The Junaluska School of Religion was a summer program sponsored by the Duke School of Religion at Lake Junaluska, N.C. From the late 1920s to early 1940s, Methodist scholars and leaders attended the summer school. The collection mainly consists of correspondence, as well as reports, recommendations, registration cards, and other materials. Major subjects include the school's administration, student enrollment, curriculum, and planning. English.
UA.19.01.0002
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Junaluska School of Religion Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1977 (A77-152).
Historical Note
From the late 1928 to the about 1941, the Duke School of Religion sponsored a summer school program at Lake Junaluska in western North Carolina. Called the Junaluska School of Religion, the program allowed Methodist leaders and scholars to gather and take college-level courses in theology. Due to a decline in enrollment and teachers, the program was discontinued in the early 1940s.
Collection Overview
The collection mainly includes correspondence, as well as reports, recommendations, registration cards, and other materials. Major topics include the administration of the school, student enrollment, curriculum, and planning.
Subject Headings
Duke School of Religion; Duke University. Divinity School; Duke University. Divinity School -- History; Lake Junaluska (N.C.); Methodist Church; Methodist Church -- North Carolina; Methodist Church -- Study and teaching -- United States; Methodist theological seminaries -- North Carolina
Description of the Collection
- General Correspondence
  - 1928 (Box 1)
  - January 1929-July 1929 (Box 1)
  - August 1929-October 1929 (Box 1)
  - November 1929 (Box 1)
  - December 1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930, [3 folders] (Box 1)
  - 1931 (Box 1)
  - 1932 (Box 1)
  - 1933 (Box 1)
  - 1935 (Box 1)
  - 1936 (Box 1)
  - 1937, [3 folders] (Box 1)
  - A-B, 1938 (Box 1)
  - C, 1938 (Box 1)
  - D-J, 1938, [2 folders] (Box 1)
  - K-R, 1938, [2 folders] (Box 2)
  - S-Z, 1938 (Box 2)
  - A-B, 1939, [2 folders] (Box 2)
  - C-E, 1939 (Box 2)
  - F-J, 1939 (Box 2)
  - K-N, 1939, [2 folders] (Box 2)
  - O-R, 1939 (Box 2)
  - S-V, 1939 (Box 2)
  - W-Z, 1939 (Box 2)
  - 1940 (Box 2)
  - 1941 (Box 2)
- Other Materials
  - Curriculum, 1928 (Box 2)
  - Registration Cards, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Photograph of Faculty and Students, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Report, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Recommendation, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Printed Announcement, 1941 (Box 2)
Related Material
School of Religion records
Duke University Archives